CHRISTOPHER CONI FY WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- ceconley4@gmail.com
- ceconley.github.io/personal-portfolio/
- **(**607)221-1961
- **Q** Greater Providence Area
- in linkedin.com/in/christopher-conley
- **?** ceconley

SUMMARY

My background is in leading large teams. I have worked for 2 Fortune 500 companies in the retail environment. This allowed me to fulfill 1 of my 2 main passions. I love working on teams of people with diverse perspectives. My other passion is using analytical thinking to solve complex technical problems. When I decided to branch out and expand my skills, I started with data analytics. This eventually led me to coding and web development. Now, every day I'm doing something love. Whether I'm building projects, fixing bugs or collaborating with my peers, the time just flies.

DATA ANALYSIS

SOL

Excel

Tableau

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

JQuery

AJAX

Rubv

Rails

PostgreSQL

Node.js

Express

Mongo DB SASS

Bootstrap

Handlebars

PROJECTS

TIC TAC TOE

- -Built a single page web application from scratch, without a starter codebase.
- -Built to a spec that someone else gave me.
- -Used my programming skills to write a custom game engine for Tic Tac Toe.
- -I used AJAX to interact with a provided API, to create and store game states.
- -Future iterations will allow for multi-player/multi-device game-play.
- -Created documentation and practiced version control, file management and proper code styling.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap

EXPENSE TRACKER

- -Built an expense tracking, single-page application with basic user authentication.
- -The Frontend interacts with a custom API that I built.
- -The backend was built using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- -This app allows a signed-in user to create, read, update, and delete data in a Psql database.
- -The user controls these actions on the frontend, along with the ability to organize and analyze the data returned.

Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap and Handlebars

INVENTORY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- -First time working in a group environment as a developer.
- -The 4 group members all started at different levels of ability and understanding.
- -First day was spent creating a group culture-code and going through old code, to get on the same page.
- -One obstacles we ran into was Git workflow, but we were able to overcome them pretty easily.
- -Another issue was members not meeting deadlines, so we had to figure out how to pick up that slack.
- -Ultimately we met the MVP by the deadline.
- -The project was an Inventory Management System for an online retailer.
- -It was a full stack, single page application, using Express and Mongo for the backend.

Technologies Used: Express.Js, MongoDB, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and Handlebars

DAILY FANTASY CHAMPS

- -With projects 2 & 3 being more business oriented, I wanted my capstone to be something more fun.
- -I enjoy playing daily fantasy sports, so I decided to make a fantasy football single page application.
- -This allows players to select from pre-made lineups and enter them in different contests.
- -There were 2 major challenges I put on myself for this project:
 - 1. There are 3 resources that all have a many-to-many relationships with each other.
 - 2. The user doesn't have to input any information once they are logged in.

Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, ¡Query, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and Handlebars

EMPLOYMENT

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Fellow

I built 4 projects in an immersive, 12 week, 500+ hour, web development training program. We focused on utilizing modern full-stack programming languages, frameworks, version control, and agile methodology.

SELF EMPLOYED

East Greenwich, RI 2018 to Current

I managed a small fund, using learned trading methods and risk management strategies to generate profitable results.

RETAIL MANAGEMENT

Commodity and Equity Derivatives Trader

General Manager

NY, CT, MA 2005 to 2018

Providence, RI

2018 to 2019

For 13 years I was a Retail Manager for 2 Fortune 500 and 1 of Forbes Top Private Companies. I held roles ranging from Department Supervisor to Store Manager. During this time I led small and large teams and won multiple awards for Operations, Sales and Profit.

EDUCATION

STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW YORK - CORTLAND

B.S. Business Economics